<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Blue Palo Alto]]></title>
  <link href="http://bluepaloalto.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://bluepaloalto.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-12-29T18:14:54-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://bluepaloalto.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mark L. Fussell]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interest? Kickstarter!]]></title>
    <link href="http://bluepaloalto.github.io/blog/interest-kickstarter/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-29T15:17:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://bluepaloalto.github.io/blog/interest-kickstarter</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There is now a Kickstarter at: <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/761729676/blue-palo-alto">https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/761729676/blue-palo-alto</a></p>

<p>This is to gauge interest in the whole idea, and to enable people to participate in the transformation/revitalization.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Problem! Opportunity!]]></title>
    <link href="http://bluepaloalto.github.io/blog/problem-opportunity/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-20T15:17:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://bluepaloalto.github.io/blog/problem-opportunity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Palo Alto is the epicenter of the technology world.  Nearby towns sometimes get mentioned too
(Facebook is now in a strange part of Menlo Park, Google is on the shores of Mountain View,
and the truly insanely wealthy always own something in Portola Valley), but everything starts in Palo Alto.
Even the institute that labels itself Stanford is actually <em>in</em> Palo Alto (Palo Alto police, fire, etc.)</p>

<p>The strange thing about Palo Alto is that it was a vacation place half a century or more ago.  So the housing is
quite cheap.  Nice houses in San Francisco.  Cheap houses in Palo Alto.  Almost like log cabins.</p>

<p>Fast-forward 50+ years, and we have log cabins on $1.5MM lots.  That makes absolutely no sense.  Having crappy
houses on $1.5MM lots is completely insane.  Replacing crappy houses with $0.5MM custom built mansions also makes
no sense.  They are ugly, too big, too noisy during construction, and
$0.5MM built on-site is not really enough money to do something right.</p>

<h2>Opportunity</h2>

<p>In the last decade or so, modular, factory-built, homes have become viable.  They are a little too expensive
because too few people buy them.  Factories get cheaper as demand gets larger.  Eventually Teslas will cost less
than $40K and will be an incredibly good deal.  iPhones are <em>an amazing deal</em> for the price.  As are its competitors.</p>

<p>A $0.5MM factory-built home is actually worth more like $1.0MM on-site.  Or definitely more than the $0.5MM home plus
the $0.25MM permit, foundation, and install cost.</p>

<p>So lets prove that!  Take a $1.5MM lot, throw away the log cabin on it, put a $0.5MM factory-built, beautiful, and
super-modern home on the lot, and see what that is worth.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>At current housing prices, it should be about $1K to $1.5K per square foot.  That could be a 25% to even 50% ROI.  In
three months or even a year, that would be fantastic.</p>

<h2>Timeline</h2>

<p>I am working on everything <em>now</em>.  Houses do move during the winter in Palo Alto, but the <em>prime season</em> starts in
April and May because Palo Alto has an unusually good school district for California.  So people with kids want to
start moving into the school district.  Actually school registration starts in February, so people should really acquire
before then.</p>

<h2>Offer</h2>

<p>I will handle <em>everything</em> about finding and acquiring the right kind of lot, setbacks, general contracting, permits, Palo Alto
specific regulations, Palo Alto politics (and how to avoid), agents, etc.
The lot and the house will be <em>yours</em>, and you will need to pay for everything associated with it.  It is yours and
you can do with it what you want, but depending on what you want to do with it, I will find the right location.
For example, if you want to show it off, I will find a property on a major or secondary
artery, or in a beautiful neighborhood where you can take people to it.</p>

<h2>Who are you?</h2>

<p>First, you must be able to <em>fund this</em>.  I want to deal with <em>one person</em> who holds the checkbook for your entity.
I get paid an insane amount of money for my time, but that is because I am incredibly efficient and effective for
my clients.  You must be able to execute without wasting my time.  And in exchange I promise not to waste yours.</p>

<p>You can take things slow: you can ponder on your own, have a BOD meeting, etc. but don&rsquo;t
expect me to attend the things that cause you delays.  Just work them out within your organization
and then tell me what you want.  I will happily show you around Palo Alto or take you to lunch at The Sea, but
unless you are going to pay my hourly rate, don&rsquo;t expect me to hang out for hours on a phone call.</p>

<p>Second, you must either have an amazing product (say you are Blu or LivingHomes) and want to showcase it, or
you have enough money to fund a house and are just looking for a good ROI.  If you are in the second category,
you can either suggest houses you like or let my team pick what seems like the best ROI for the properties
that are currently available (and the dynamics of Palo Alto).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Site Launch!]]></title>
    <link href="http://bluepaloalto.github.io/blog/site-launch/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-19T15:17:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://bluepaloalto.github.io/blog/site-launch</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I visited <a href="http://BluHomes.com/">http://BluHomes.com/</a>&rsquo;s factory and sample house in Vallejo.  Basically this was the culmination of an idea / venture that
was brewing in my head.  With this blog, I will start describing the venture / opportunity for investors to consider and also
as a real-time example of a &lsquo;hyper-startup&rsquo;: a startup executing so fast and furiously that it will make more money than
anyone could imagine in less time and with fewer people than seems possible.</p>

<p>It will seem &ldquo;inconceivable&rdquo;: please watch the Princess Bride to truly understand that word.</p>

<h2>Who am I?</h2>

<p>I am a serial entrepreneur that got incredibly good at executing startups.  To the point where I can launch companies
with internal IT (e.g. email, shares, etc.) and production IT (think Google or Apple servers) and startup-specific
functionality.  After doing the tenth of these startups, I stopped and went on to other things.  Now I am primarily
a software patent expert and help companies like Apple, HP, and Hughes either make a lot of money (Offense) or not lose <em>any</em> money (Defense).  I am
pretty efficient and effective at this, so I also have a lot of free time to help other people out.  So in total, to
get to know me better see the following:</p>

<ul>
<li> LinkedIn profile: <a href="http://linkedin.com/in/markfussell">http://linkedin.com/in/markfussell</a></li>
<li> Primary Book: <a href="http://SlumsOfPaloAlto.com">http://SlumsOfPaloAlto.com</a></li>
<li> Teaching others (kids) how to publish: <a href="http://MinimalBuyableBook.com">http://MinimalBuyableBook.com</a></li>
<li> Going to the US Open in Tennis: <a href="http://SupersonicFox.com">http://SupersonicFox.com</a></li>
<li> Helping sports instructors: <a href="http://InsanelyGreatTennis.com">http://InsanelyGreatTennis.com</a></li>
<li> Helping farmers: <a href="http://FullOfLifeFood.com">http://FullOfLifeFood.com</a></li>
<li> Teaching robotics: <a href="http://PaloBots.com">http://PaloBots.com</a></li>
<li> &hellip;</li>
</ul>


<p>And now, there is this site, which will transform a community for the better while making investors a lot of money.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
