<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Blue Palo Alto]]></title>
  <link href="http://bluepaloalto.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://bluepaloalto.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-12-19T14:47:48-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://bluepaloalto.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mark L. Fussell]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Site Launch!]]></title>
    <link href="http://bluepaloalto.github.io/blog/site-launch/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-19T15:17:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://bluepaloalto.github.io/blog/site-launch</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I visited <a href="http://BluHomes.com/">http://BluHomes.com/</a>&rsquo;s factory and sample house in Vallejo.  Basically this was the culmination of an idea / venture that
was brewing in my head.  With this blog, I will start describing the venture / opportunity for investors to consider and also
as a real-time example of a &lsquo;hyper-startup&rsquo;: a startup executing so fast and furiously that it will make more money than
anyone could imagine in less time and with fewer people than seems possible.</p>

<p>It will seem &ldquo;inconceivable&rdquo;: please watch the Princess Bride to truly understand that word.</p>

<h2>Who am I?</h2>

<p>I am a serial entrepreneur that got incredibly good at executing startups.  To the point where I can launch companies
with internal IT (e.g. email, shares, etc.) and production IT (think Google or Apple servers) and startup-specific
functionality.  After doing the tenth of these startups, I stopped and went on to other things.  Now I am primarily
a software patent expert and help companies like Apple, HP, and Hughes either make or not lose a lot of money.  I am
pretty efficient and effective at this, so I also have a lot of free time to help other people out.  So in total, to
get to know me better see the following:</p>

<ul>
<li> LinkedIn profile: <a href="http://linkedin.com/in/markfussell">http://linkedin.com/in/markfussell</a></li>
<li> Primary Book: <a href="http://SlumsOfPaloAlto.com">http://SlumsOfPaloAlto.com</a></li>
<li> Teaching others (kids) how to publish: <a href="http://MinimalBuyableBook.com">http://MinimalBuyableBook.com</a></li>
<li> Going to the US Open in Tennis: <a href="http://SupersonicFox.com">http://SupersonicFox.com</a></li>
<li> Helping sports instructors: <a href="http://InsanelyGreatTennis.com">http://InsanelyGreatTennis.com</a></li>
<li> Helping farmers: <a href="http://FullOfLifeFood.com">http://FullOfLifeFood.com</a></li>
<li> &hellip;</li>
</ul>


<p>And now, there is this site, which will transform a community for the better while making investors a lot of money.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
